<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uli&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Uli&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 14:40:53 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool Programing Languages</title>
      <link>/posts/cool-programing-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 14:40:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/cool-programing-languages/</guid>
      <description>I felt like writing a list of interesting programing languages for people who care. NOTE: Interesting does not mean &amp;ldquo;better then everything else at everything&amp;rdquo;, also many popular programming languages get the job done but are not on this list (like python) because they are already established.
Here&#39;s the list in no perticular order, also won&#39;t be commenting on them much since their website can usually sell it quite well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If Programming Languages Were Moms</title>
      <link>/posts/if-programming-languages-were-moms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 22:31:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/if-programming-languages-were-moms/</guid>
      <description>This is clearly biased from the languages I like better, hopefully fun to read anyways.
Rust Is kindly and protective. A bit overreaching at times but you know its for your own good, and if you beg her she&#39;ll let you do whatever you want.
Haskell Is an overprotective parent, You might understand her rules better if you had a PhD in math and studied category theory though.
Python Is a huge proponent of teamwork, often when you want to do something she will immediately find 5 experts in the topic, she can be quite slow though if you need to do something yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nodejs Encryption</title>
      <link>/posts/nodejs-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 21:39:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/nodejs-encryption/</guid>
      <description>I hate javascript But I&#39;m using it to write a discord bot, for a few reasons (mostly the awesome discordjs api) I desided it was the easiest way to get my friends into programming via writing discord bots.
So, I thought it would be cool to add encryption-decryption functionality to my bot.
I&#39;m a perfectionist so I wanted nothing less then aes256-gcm + a good KDF (I picked scrypt), Since I&#39;m quite minimal, I desided to use the crypto package provided by node Instead of grabbing an insecure unmaintained package from npm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>__index horror</title>
      <link>/posts/index_horror/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 19:47:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/index_horror/</guid>
      <description>The problem Lua is a great programming language, very nice for modding games and super simple.
lua has a feature called metatables they are super useful, this post talks about the metatable event __index
the __index metatable event allows you to do something special when a key is not found in a table, for example here is how it can be used to look in another table if a key is not found</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>/posts/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 21:49:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/first-post/</guid>
      <description>This is my first blog post! just gonna test some markdown.
def my_first_function(): print(&amp;#34;i would never write a function this boring&amp;#34;) shell syntax highlighting?
if [ &amp;#34;$*&amp;#34; = &amp;#34;i like cats&amp;#34; ]; then echo &amp;#34;You have good taste&amp;#34; else echo &amp;#34;Get out of my sight&amp;#34; fi </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 19:14:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi there My name is Uli and I was born in 2004. I made it so I could write about the things I learn and hopefully someone else can benifit from it too.
Contact If you need to contact me, for any reason there are a few places.
I have a matrix account that I use for my main communication with friends, having moved away from discord because of its lack of end to end encryption My matrix username is valvate</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>