<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>untagged on Uli&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>/tags/untagged/</link>
    <description>Recent content in untagged on Uli&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 22:31:04 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/untagged/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>If Programming Languages Were Moms</title>
      <link>/posts/if-programming-languages-were-moms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 22:31:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/if-programming-languages-were-moms/</guid>
      <description>This is clearly biased from the languages I like better, hopefully fun to read anyways.
Rust Is kindly and protective. A bit overreaching at times but you know its for your own good, and if you beg her she&#39;ll let you do whatever you want.
Haskell Is an overprotective parent, You might understand her rules better if you had a PhD in math and studied category theory though.
Python Is a huge proponent of teamwork, often when you want to do something she will immediately find 5 experts in the topic, she can be quite slow though if you need to do something yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nodejs Encryption</title>
      <link>/posts/nodejs-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 21:39:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/nodejs-encryption/</guid>
      <description>I hate javascript But I&#39;m using it to write a discord bot, for a few reasons (mostly the awesome discordjs api) I desided it was the easiest way to get my friends into programming via writing discord bots.
So, I thought it would be cool to add encryption-decryption functionality to my bot.
I&#39;m a perfectionist so I wanted nothing less then aes256-gcm + a good KDF (I picked scrypt), Since I&#39;m quite minimal, I desided to use the crypto package provided by node Instead of grabbing an insecure unmaintained package from npm.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>